[
  {
    "question": "What is the default message retention time in Azure Event Hub?",
    "options": ["30 minutes", "1 hour", "1 day", "10 days"],
    "correct_answer": 2,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum message retention time in Azure Event Hub?",
    "options": ["30 days", "7 days", "1 day", "10 days"],
    "correct_answer": 1,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main use case of Azure Event Hub?",
    "options": [
      "Ingestion of low volume messages from Azure services",
      "Ingestion of high volume events from many different sources",
      "Ingestion of high volume messages from many different sources",
      "Connecting full duplex communication between two cloud providers"
    ],
    "correct_answer": 1,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the two protocols supported by Azure Event Hub?",
    "options": [
      "HTTPS and AMQP",
      "AMQP and MQTT",
      "HTTPS ans MQTT",
      "All of above"
    ],
    "correct_answer": 0,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many concurrent AMQP connections are supported by Azure Event Hub?",
    "options": ["5 Million", "1 Million", "1 Thousand", "5 Thousand"],
    "correct_answer": 3,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many event hubs can a event hub namespace contain?",
    "options": ["1", "5", "10", "30"],
    "correct_answer": 2,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "How much capacity can 1 throughput unit handle?",
    "options": [
      "1 MB/s or 1000 events/s ingress and 2 MB/s or 2000 events/s egress",
      "2 MB/s or 2000 events/s ingress and 2 MB/s or 2000 events/s egress",
      "2 MB/s or 2000 events/s ingress and 1 MB/s or 1000 events/s egress",
      "10 MB/s or 10000 events/s ingress and 10 MB/s or 10000 events/s egress"
    ],
    "correct_answer": 0,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "A throughput is defined in the event hub namespace and is shared among contained event hubs?",
    "options": ["True", "False"],
    "correct_answer": 0,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "Auto-inflate is defined in the event hub namespace?",
    "options": ["True", "False"],
    "correct_answer": 0,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens when senders send more than the throughput capacity of an event hub without auto-inflate?",
    "options": [
      "Throughput capacity will automatically adjusted to handle capacity.",
      "Senders will be throttled, receiving errors.",
      "Event hub will buffer the messages in a storage queue.",
      "Senders will automatically blocked by event hub for a predefined period"
    ],
    "correct_answer": 1,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum throughput units configured to an event hub namespace?",
    "options": ["5", "10", "20", "100"],
    "correct_answer": 2,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the default throughput units configured to an event hub namespace?",
    "options": ["5", "10", "20", "1"],
    "correct_answer": 3,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "A throughput unit will be shared among contained event hubs evenly in a fixed amount even if they are not being used?",
    "options": ["True", "False"],
    "correct_answer": 1,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "Auto-inflate will decrease the throughput units after the load is reduced?",
    "options": ["True", "False"],
    "correct_answer": 1,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "One can have more than 20 throughput units by submitting a support ticket?",
    "options": ["True", "False"],
    "correct_answer": 0,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an event hub partition?",
    "options": [
      "It is a container that helps paralelize consumption of events",
      "It is a special container that uses a user defined logic for processing events"
    ],
    "correct_answer": 0,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "How the events are distributed among partitions?",
    "options": [
      "According to configured filters",
      "Prioritize the one with less load",
      "Round robin",
      "Randomly"
    ],
    "correct_answer": 2,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the default value and minimum number of partitions an event hub can have?",
    "options": [
      "1 is the default and minimum number of partitions",
      "2 is the default and minimum number of partitions",
      "2 is the default and 1 is the minimum number of partitions",
      "1 is the default and 2 is the minimum number of partitions"
    ],
    "correct_answer": 1,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "New events are added to the end of a partition?",
    "options": ["True", "False"],
    "correct_answer": 0,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "The number of partitions are defined in the event hub namespace?",
    "options": ["True", "False, it is defined in the event hub."],
    "correct_answer": 1,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many GB storage per day is included in 1 throughput unit?",
    "options": ["1 GB", "10 GB", "84 GB", "100 GB"],
    "correct_answer": 2,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "The number of partitions can be changed after event hub creation?",
    "options": ["True", "False"],
    "correct_answer": 1,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  },
  {
    "question": "The number of partitions should be proportional to the number of concurrent consumers?",
    "options": ["True", "False"],
    "correct_answer": 0,
    "category": "Azure Event Hub"
  }
]
